以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好的开始我以为我会
ok getting getting started I thought I'd
添加一些关于这个问题的话
add a few words about a question that
在课后假设出现了
came up after class suppose in that
上次讨论你在哪里
discussion last time where you were
给了三个你给了一个距离
given three you were given a distance
矩阵你得到了距离
matrix you were given the distance
介于x2和x2之间x2和x3之间
between x1 and x2 between x2 and x3 and
在x1和x3之间你想找到
between x1 and x3 and you wanted to find
我们满意的要点
points that satisfied that well we're
要失败在这个例子中，因为如果
going to fail on this example because if
这里的距离为1的距离在这里
the distance here is 1 the distance here
是1，那么通过三角不等式的
is 1 then by the triangle inequality the
从x1到x3的距离不能太多
distance from x1 to x3 could not be more
超过2，当我们摆正它时它可以
than 2 and when we square it it could
不超过4，这里是6
not be more than 4 and here it's 6 so
什么会发生什么问题
what's going to happen what goes wrong
在那种情况下，是的，我没有评论过
in that case yeah I hadn't commented on
这一点，我不知道是该
that and I'm not sure that that the
我引用的论文是这样的，所以我有
paper that I referenced does so so I had
做一点回顾
to do a little search back in the
人们不能忽视文学
literature cuz people couldn't overlook
这个问题所以这是三角形
this problem so this is the triangle
不平等失败，所以它不是
inequality fails so that and it's not
将帮助进入十个维度
going to help to go into ten dimensions
因为三角不等式没有
because the triangle inequality doesn't
不会改变，它仍然存在
doesn't change and it's still there in
十个维度，我们仍然失败
ten dimensions and we're still failing
它会发生什么事情呢？
it so what happens well what could
发生
happen
你记得吗，你必须这样做
do you remember and you'll have to
提醒我你的关键等式
remind me the the key equation you
记得我们有一个方程式连接
remember we had an equation connecting
连接那么矩阵D是什么
connecting so what is the matrix D for
这个问题，让d是，这是一个三通过
this problem so D is this is a three by
具有这些距离的三个矩阵
three matrix with these distances
平方，这是方便使用
squared and it was convenient to use
距离平方因为那是什么
distances squared because that's what
当然，我会进入下一步
comes into the next steps so of course
从每个X到它自身的距离是0
the distance from each X to itself is 0
距x平方的距离是
the distance from x distance squared was
这是一个，但这个是6
that this one was that but this one is 6
好的，这就是距离矩阵和我们
ok so that's the distance matrix and we
我想找工作找
would like to find the job was to find
一周，我只想写下我们
week and I'm just going to write down we
找不到x1x2和x3也不匹配
cannot find x1 x2 and x3 too to match
那些距离所以出了什么问题
those distances so what goes wrong well
只有一件事可以发生
there's only one thing that could go
连接此距离时错误
wrong when you connect this distance
矩阵D到矩阵X转置X你
matrix D to the matrix X transpose X you
记住位置矩阵也许我
remember the position matrix maybe I
称之为G，这就是GIJ
called it G this this is giving so G IJ
是XI与XJoops的点积
is the dot product of X I with XJ oops
作出这样的成为J在这里谢谢你这么g^
make that into a J here thank you so g
IJ是点积和矩阵
IJ is the matrix of dot products and the
伟大的事情是我们可以发现
great thing was that we can discover
矩阵G来自哪个矩阵
what that matrix that matrix G comes
直接来自D直接来自D.
directly from D comes directly from D
当然我们怎么知道这个
and of course what do we know about this
我们知道它的交叉产品矩阵
matrix of cross products we know that it
是半正定的
is positive semi-definite
所以在一句话中出了问题
so what goes wrong well just in a word
当我们写的是方程
when we write out that equation and
发现三角形是什么G
discover what G is if the triangle
不平等失败我们知道G是G
inequality fails we learn that G is G
并不是肯定的
doesn't come out positive definite
这就是我想说的全部和我
that's really all I want to say and I
可以推动G的例子
could push through the example G will
如果D如果，那就不是肯定的
not come out positive definite if D if
这是D，因为如果它出来它就不能
that's D because it can't if it came out
肯定的，然后我们可以找到一个
positive definite then we could find an
X所以，如果我们有G，那么最后一步
X so if we had the G then the final step
你还记得我们找到一个X井
you remember is to find an X well we
知道如果G是半正定的
know that if G is positive semi-definite
有多种方法可以找到x你
there are multiple ways to find an x you
知道这是正半确定的
know this is positive semi definite
矩阵就是你从X中获得的
matrices is what you get out of X
转置Xs我们可以找到一个给定的x
transpose X s and we can find an x given
我们可以找到G得到一个X所以它有
a G we can find G given an X so it has
是，这不会是真实的，
to be that this won't be true that the
矩阵G来自该等式
matrix G that comes out of that equation
会变成不为正
will turn out not to be positive
确定所以这真的很不错
definite so it's it's really quite nice
这是一个美丽的一点点
it's a beautiful little bit of
数学，如果当且仅当
mathematics that if if and only if the
三角不等式得到满足
triangle inequality is satisfied by
这些数字当且仅当时
these numbers if and only if then the
然后在D矩阵中的矩阵
matrix that in the in the D matrix then
即这样来的G矩阵
the G matrix that comes out of this
我没写过的等式是
equation which I haven't written is
如果三角形是正半正定的
positive semi-definite if the triangle
不平等是可以的，我们可以找到
inequality is okay we can find the
如果三角形不等式是分数
points if the triangle inequality is
像这里我们那样违反了矩阵G.
violated like here we then the matrix G
不是半正定的
is not positive semi-definite has
负特征值，我们找不到
negative eigenvalues and we cannot find
关键是我能记得G
the point yeah I could recall the G
矩阵
matrix
G等式，但它来了
the the G equation but it's coming to
你在两页的部分
you in the two page section that does
只是距离矩阵好吧那就是
just distance matrices okay that that's
我有点喜欢这样做
just I sort of like made a point it's
很高兴有特定的数字和我
nice to have specific numbers and I
可以得到G和的具体数字
could get the specific numbers for G and
我们不会认为这不是积极的
we would see no way it's not positive
确定好，所以这只是整理
definite okay so that's just tidying up
上次我有另一个小问题
last time I have another small problem
谈论，然后一个大问题
to talk about and then a big question of
深度学习是否真的有效我
whether deep learning actually works I
昨晚有专家发来的电子邮件
had an email from an expert last night
这改变了我对世界的看法
which changed my view of the world about
这个问题，你可以想像的了
that question as you can imagine the the
改变我的世界是我曾经想过的
change in my world was I had thought the
答案是肯定的，我现在认为
answer was yes and I now think the
答案不是没有，所以这就像是一个
answer isn't no so that's like rather a
十八六五的大问题但是
big issue for eighteen oh six five but
我们将让我们看到以后好吗
we'll let's see about that later okay
还好我现在就ProQuest的这些问题，所以
okay now I'll proquest these problem so
prouKrusty和我把它包括在内
prou Krusty's and i it's included in the
注意到这个名字来自希腊语
notes it's that name comes from a Greek
神话是你们到希腊神话等等
myth are you guys into Greek myths so
每个Krusty的故事是什么？
what was the story of per Krusty's he
在Procrustes调整了
was at Procrustes who adjusted the
他的长度让他有一张特别的床
lengths of his so he had a special bed
对于crusties床一定长度和
for crusties bed certain lengths and
然后他有来访的游客
then he had visitors coming and instead
的调节所述床的所述长度
of adjusting the length of the bed to
适合Krusty调整后的访客
fit the visitor for Krusty's adjusted
适合床的访客的长度
the length of the visitor to fit the bed
所以要么拉伸访客，要么切碎
so either stretch the visitor or chopped
离
off
访客的一部分，所以无论如何它是它的
part of the visitor so anyway it's it's
希腊人这样或东西好了，
the Greeks like this or a thing okay so
无论如何，那是希腊神话
anyway that's that's a Greek myth for
十八，六，六，好，所以整个
eighteen oh six five okay so the whole
想法有打击茶的问题是
idea there percuss teas problem is to
做一些适合别的东西所以
make something fit something else so the
所以这两件事情都是如此假设我
so the two things are so suppose I'm
我只有三个维度
just in three dimensions I have two
这里向量排序的基础
vectors here sort of a basis for a
二维空间和我在这里
two-dimensional space and over here I
有太空科学家可能有的人
have people space scientists might have
一个位置的计算
one computation of the of the positions
当然他们是卫星
of satellites then of course they
不会多达这是关
wouldn't be off by as much as this
图显示但是他们有另一个
figure shows but then they have another
使用不同坐标计算
computation using different coordinates
所以它是部分旋转的
so it so it's it's partly rotated from
这张照片，但它也部分得到了
this picture but also it's partly got
舍入错误和错误
roundoff errors and an error in it
两者之间所以问题是
between the two so the question is
什么是最好的正交
what's the best best orthogonal
改造所以这是一个
transformation so this is this is a
一堆矢量X1X22Xn让我们说
bunch of vectors X 1 X 2 2 X n let's say
我想把它们乘以一个
and I want to multiply them by an
正交矩阵没有，我可能会这样做
orthogonal matrix no maybe I'd do it on
另一边，我觉得我做的啊Q的
the other side I think I do yeah q to be
尽可能接近另一套Y.
as close as possible to this other set Y
1y2到Yn所以让我说吧
1 y 2 up to Y n so let me just say it
再次
again
我有两组矢量而且我是
I have two sets of vectors and I'm
看起来和他们不一样
looking and they're different like those
两套，我正在寻找
two sets and I'm looking for the
正交矩阵以及
orthogonal matrix that as well as
可能将此集合纳入此中
possible takes this set into this one of
当然，如果这是如果这是一个
course if this was if this was an
正交基础，这是一个
orthogonal basis and this was an
正交基
orthogonal basis
那么我们就可以回家免费问：我们能
then we would be home free q we could
得到平等，我们可以采取正交
get equality we could take an orthogonal
直接基于正交基础
basis directly into an orthogonal basis
在其他情况下使用正交矩阵Q.
with a orthogonal matrix Q in other
如果X是正交矩阵，则为单词
words if X was an orthogonal matrix and
Y是我们得到的正交矩阵
Y was an orthogonal matrix we would get
这是完全正确的q，但事实并非如此
it the exact correct q but that's not
这样的话我们正在寻找最好的
the case so we're looking for the best
可能这样就是问题所在
possible so that's the the problem then
如果我最小化过正交，则最小化
minimize if I minimize over orthogonal
矩阵矩阵Q和我只想得到
matrix matrices Q and I just want to get
我的符号在这里保持一致没关系
my notation to be consistent here okay
好的，所以我看到我开始了
okay so I've I see that I starting with
Y和将它们映射到X的所以让我们
the Y's and mapping them to X's so let
我问什么都般的暴徒“厄尔尼诺问题
me ask the question what are thuggin 'el
矩阵q乘以Y来表示
matrix q multiplies the Y's to come as
尽可能接近x，所以我
close as possible to the x's so so I
在我想要的所有正交Q上
over all orthogonal Q's I want to
在Frobenius中最小化YQ减去X.
minimize Y Q minus X in the Frobenius
因此Frobenius我们进入了平常
norm squared so Frobenius we're into the
Frobenius规范记得矩阵
Frobenius norm remember the of a matrix
这是一个非常方便的诺曼德
this is a very convenient Normand in
数据科学来衡量一个人的规模
data science to measure the size of a
矩阵，我们有几种可能
matrix and we have several possible
它的公式所以让我打电话
formulas for it so the so let me call
矩阵a和Frobenius范数
the matrix a and the Frobenius norm
平方
squared
好吧那么这就是一个表达方式
okay so what's one expression in terms
矩阵条目的数字
of the entries of the matrix the numbers
一个IJ和基质中的Frobenius范数
a IJ and the matrix the Frobenius norm
只是把它像一个长的矢量如此
is just treats it like a long vector so
它是1平方加1平方
it's a 1 1 squared plus a 1 2 squared
一路
all the way
我会说第一到第二行
the first plus second row just I'll say
NN所有的方块的平方之和确定
n n square ok sum of all the squares
只是将它视为长矢量好吧
just treating it like a long vector okay
这个，但这是一个尴尬的表达
this but that's a awkward expression to
写下来
write down
那么我们还有什么方法可以找到
so what other ways do we have to find
我们可以看到矩阵的Frobenius范数
the Frobenius norm of a matrix let's see
我可以把它看成是一个转置
I can look at this as a transpose a is
那个正确的转置一个什么是什么的
that right a transpose a so what what's
发生在那里
happening there
提醒我，是的，我会得到所有
remind me what yeah I I would get all
我会通过拿走所有这些
that I would get all these by taking the
矩阵a转置时间a但是什么
matrix a transpose times a but what
对不起，我不是，我不是我没有我
sorry I'm not I'm not I haven't I've
在这里失去了我的谈话威胁
lost my threat of of talk here
所以这是哦，然后我走了踪迹
so here's oh and then I take the trace
当然这样第一排第一列
of course so that first row first column
有一次会给我一个
of a times that one will give me the one
一组正方形然后那一次
set of squares and then that one times
另一个人会给我
the other one the next one will give me
下一组正方形就是这样
the next set of squares right so this is
去，如果我在跟踪看起来那么现在
going to if I look at the trace so now
让我，所以我只是想看看
let me I so I'm just want to look at the
对角线在这里，所以它是跟踪你
diagonal here so it's it's the trace you
记住一个矩阵的痕迹
remember the trace of a matrix of a
矩阵M是一个人M11M2
matrix M is some down the guy M 1 1 M 2
2到mmm
2 down to mmm
这是一个对角的太阳和一个
it's it's some it's a diagonal Sun and a
我这里的每个人现在都是如此
everybody with me here is now the so
这个术语在转置的对角线上
that term on the diagonal of a transpose
a然后给我所有这些或者也许
a gives me all of that then or maybe
我也许我应该做一个
I've maybe I should be doing a a
转置，重点是它没有
transpose and the point is it doesn't
重要的是，或者是一个转置的痕迹
matter so or the trace of a a transpose
那些都会给予给予
that would be those would both give give
正确的弗罗贝尼乌斯范数如此平方
the correct Frobenius norm squared so
痕迹将进入这个
traces are going to come into this
小问题
little problem
现在还有另一个公式
now there's another formula for the
弗罗贝尼乌斯的规范甚至更短
Frobenius norm even shorter well
肯定比这短
certainly shorter than this one
涉及一个正方形和什么的平方
involving a sum of squares and what's
那是另一种获得的方式
that one what's the other way to get
如果我看一下SVD就会得到同样的答案
this same answer if I look at the SVD
看奇异值我认为，
look at singular values I think that
这也等于西格玛
this is also equal to Sigma what are
所有奇异值的某个方格
some square of all the singular values
所以它是三个很好的表达式
so it's three nice expressions for the
Frobenius规范好的涉及一个
Frobenius norm the nice ones involve a
转置a或aa转置和
transpose a or a a transpose and of
连接到单数的课程
course that connects to the singular
价值因为什么是什么
values because what are what's the
奇异值与。之间的联系
connection between singular values and
那些和这些家伙改变一个或一个
those and these guys a transpose a or a
a转置奇异值是
a transpose the the singular values are
的或正方形的奇异值是
the or the singular value squared are
转置a和a的特征值
the eigenvalues of a transpose a and
然后，当我添加我正在添加的跟踪
then when I add up the trace I'm adding
提高了特征值，那就是那个
up the eigen values and that's the that
给了我Frobenius规范的平方
gives me the Frobenius norm squared so
这是一个告诉我们的东西
this is a that's a that tells us
重要的事情
something important
我们可以用不同的方式看到
which we can see in different ways that
所以我们要解决这个问题，我们要去
so we to solve this problem we're gonna
需要在各种事实，如QA
need various facts like the QA in the
Frobenius规范与a中的相同
Frobenius norm is the same as a in the
Frobenius没有为什么这就是为什么这样
Frobenius no why why is that why so here
我把每一列乘以
I'm multiplying every column by the
矩阵Q长度发生了什么
matrix Q what happens to the length of
当我乘以Q时的列
the column when I multiply it by Q
不会改变，所以我可以积少成多
doesn't change so I could add up the
列的长度都在这里平方
lengths of the columns all squared here
我用行来写它，但我
I wrote it in in terms of rows but I
本来可以重新排序并把它搞定
could have reordered that and got it in
列的术语是因为
terms of columns that's because the
任何矢量平方的Q倍的长度
length of Q times any any vector square
它与矢量平方和
it is the same as the vector square and
这些都需要这些是的列
these take these to be the columns of a
所以对于逐列来说
so for column by column the
乘用Q不改变
multiplication by Q doesn't change the
长度，然后当我把所有的加起来
length and then when I add up all the
列平方我得到的弗洛比尼范数
columns squared I get the Frobenius norm
平方和另一种方式说它让我们
squared and another way to say it let's
在这之间建立联系
make the connection between the this
事实上Q没有改变Frobenius
fact that Q didn't change the Frobenius
因此b和n这个事实
norm and this fact that therefore b
Gnaeus规范以表达方式表达
Gnaeus norm is expressed in terms of
他们的Sigma是如此，那么Q应该是什么
their Sigma's so whoa so what does Q due
我希望在另一个中看到西格玛
to the Sigma's I want to see in another
另一种方式，如果我，为什么这样的答案
another way the answer to why so if I
有一个具有奇异值I的矩阵a
have a matrix a with singular values I
乘以Q会发生什么
multiply by Q what happens to the
奇异值不改变不
singular values don't change don't
改变这是关于说的关键点
change that's the key point about saying
如果我乘以这样的话，那就是他们的价值观
to their values if I multiply so a has
一个SVDuSigmaV转置和Qa
an SVD u Sigma V transpose and Q a
我们将有SVDquSigmaV转置
we'll have the SVD qu Sigma V transpose
所以当我乘以Q时我都改变了
so all I've changed when I multiply by Q
所有我改变是第一因素
all I changed was the first factor the
SVDI中的第一个正交因子
first orthogonal factor in the SVD I
没有改变西格玛，他们仍然是
didn't change the Sigma's they're still
坐在那里，当然我可以
sitting there so and of course I could
另外Q也做Q
do also Q on the other side different Q
相同的Q或另一个不同的Q.
same Q or a different Q on the other
一方会出现在这里而不会
side would show up here and would not
改变Sigma的，因此会
change the Sigma's and therefore would
不要改变弗罗贝尼乌斯的规范
not change the Frobenius norm so that's
这些都是这一重要特性
these are important properties of this
4bGnaeus规范它看起来很混乱
4b Gnaeus norm it's a it looks messy
在那种形式下，但它是很多
right down in that form but it's much
这些形式和形式更好
nicer in these forms and in that form
好的，好吧，如果我可以那么的话
okay okay so now if I can just then then
我们看到它涉及痕迹所以让我
we saw that it involves traces so let me
对痕迹做一些观察
make a few observations about traces
好的，所以我只是想要我们想要的
okay so I'll just we want to we want to
能够玩跟踪和那是
be able to play with traces and that's
我们真的没有做过的事情
something we really haven't done here's
一个事实，即转置B的痕迹
a fact that the trace of a transpose B
等于B的轨迹转置a
is equal to the trace of B transpose a
当然，如果B是很明显，所有
of course if B is a it's clear and all
它等于Ba的痕迹
and it's equal to the trace of B a
转置所以你可以做一些改变
transpose so you can do little changes
在你的矩阵中没有改变
in your in your matrix without changing
跟踪让我们来看看，为什么这些中的一个是
the trace let's see why one of these is
为什么这是第一个陈述的原因
true why why is that first statement
真正
true
该矩阵与此有何关系？
how is that matrix related to this
矩阵它只是一个转置，如果我采取
matrix it's just a transpose if I take
我得到了那个矩阵的转置
the transpose of that matrix I get that
那么我正在添加的跟踪会发生什么
so what happens to the trace I'm adding
在对角线上，转置没有
down the diagonal the transpose has no
影响
effect
显然这只是事实
clearly this is just the fact that the
跟踪没有改变没有改变
trace doesn't change has not changed
当你转置矩阵因为
when you transpose a matrix because the
对角线现在没怎么改变了
diagonal has not changed now what about
这家伙我想我们要回去了
this guy I guess we're getting back to
老式的1806五记
old-fashioned 1806 five remembering
关于线性代数的事实，因为这个
facts about linear algebra because this
是纯线性代数所以这是什么
is pure linear algebra so what's this
一个关于
one about
这说我可以改变顺序
this says that I can reverse the order
两个矩阵的我现在在看
of two matrices I'm now looking at the
这两者之间的联系和和
connection between those two and and and
所以让我只是使用不同的
so so let me just to use different
字母CD等于DC的痕迹，我可以
letters C D equals the trace of DC I can
翻转那就是我所有的顺序
flip the order that's that's all I've
在这里完成的是我用一个转换了B.
done here is I've reversed B with a
转置我用D反转C好吧
transpose i reversed C with D okay so
为什么这才是真正的好
why is that true why is that true well
我们怎样才能看到这一事实的真相
how shall we see the truth of that fact
所以这些都是非常方便的事实
so these are really convenient facts
这使得很多人都使用了这种痕迹
that make a lot of people use the trace
比我们在1806年更常见的五个我
more often than we have in 1806 five I'm
不是基于的大论证用户
not a big user of arguments based on
追踪，但这些都是那种身份
trace but these are identities that that
与许多问题一起走了很长的路
go a long way with with many problems so
让我们来看看为什么这是真的任何时候你
let's see why that's true any time you
想想跟踪你有两个
think about trace you've got two
使用的语言可以使用
languages to use you can use the
特征值它的总和
eigenvalues it's the sum of the
特征值或你可以使用对角线
eigenvalues or you can use the diagonal
条目，因为它是的总和
entries because it's the sum of the
对角条目让我们使用特征值
diagonal entries let's use eigenvalues
如何CD的相关特征值
how are the eigenvalues of CD related to
DC的特征值它们是相同的
the eigenvalues of DC they're the same
如果这些矩阵是倾斜的
if these matrices are raked
然后可能会有一些额外的零
then there might be some extra zero like
在男人，因为他们会有
in guys because they have would have
不同的形状，但零不会
different shapes but zeros are not going
影响痕迹所以这就是
to affect the trace so so this is the
同样相同的非零特征值和好
same same nonzero eigenvalues okay and
所以，好吧，让我让我放手
so on yeah okay let me just let me let
我试着告诉你现在要采取的步骤
me try to tell you the steps now to get
正确的Q或让我告诉你
the correct Q in or let me tell you the
先回答，我意识到了
answer first and I'm realizing that the
非常重要的问题是深刻的
all-important question for does deep
学习实际上我们将要工作
learning actually work we're going to
今天没时间了，因为我们只有
run out of time today because we only
还剩几分钟
have a few minutes left
我建议我们重新提出这个问题
I suggest we bring that question back up
因为它对于一个非常重要
because like it's pretty important to a
很多人，你知道我有
lot of people there's a you know I had
与阿德尔曼教授共进午餐，他说
lunch with Professor Adelman and he said
你知道深度学习和神经网络
you know deep learning and neural nets
已经有了创纪录的数量
have had like a record amount of
公开
publicity
和炒作为一种计算
and hype for for a sort of computational
算法，但我有我的人
algorithm and but I had I've had people
现在告诉我，如果你是典型的第一
now tell me that typical first if you
使用Alex设计的网络创建
create a network using Alex's designed
例如，机会就是它
for example the chances are that it
成功不会成功
won't be successful that the successful
网络已被研究和
networks have been been worked on and
实验和良好的结构
experimented with and a good structure
已经出现，但没有出现在那里
has emerged but didn't wasn't there at
一开始所以我认为这是一个主题
the start so I think that's a topic for
星期一，我真的很好
for a Monday and I'm really just
从人说话实现
realizing from talking to people in the
那个领域
field that
这绝不是自动的
it's by no means automatic that that
结构即使你放入一个整体
structure even if you put in a whole
一堆层可能不是你的
bunch of layers it may not be what you
想要好，所以我让我完成这个
want okay so I'm let me finish this
今天的争论让我给你了
argument today let me give you the
回答这是什么好的提示
answer so what's the good cue
我有Y和X矩阵，这个想法是
I have matrices Y and X and the idea is
我把它看作Y转置X
that I take its I look at Y transpose X
所以这将是所有的点产品
so that'll be all the dot products of
一组矢量是另一组
one set of vectors were the other set of
矢量这是一个矩阵，我做了它的SVD
vectors that's a matrix and I do its SVD
你的SigmaV转置如此倍增
u Sigma V transpose so so multiply this
x转换你给予的两个基础
x trans a two bases that you're given of
当然如果Y与X相同，如果是的话
course if Y was the same as X if it was
你有一个正交的基础
an orthogonal basis you'd have the
身份没有问题，但一般我们
identity no questions but generally we
它有一个SVD，我们正在寻找
have it has an SVD and we're looking for
对于最佳的正交矩阵
the for a orthogonal matrix of the best
问是不是我的意思是它是正确的
q is doesn't it I mean it's the right
四个惊奇表达的时间
time for four expressions of amazement
它是UV转置好的，所以
it is UV transpose okay so that so
这给了我们给出的答案x
that's gives us the answer we're given x
我们正在寻找最好的q和
and y we're looking for the best q and
答案来得最简单
the answer comes in the simplest
计算Y转置X的可能方式
possible way compute Y transpose X
计算其SVD并使用正交
compute its SVD and use the orthogonal
来自SVD的矩阵是的，我出去了
matrices from the SVD yeah and I'm out
时间如此证明它是三行
of time so so proof it's it's three line
以后要么要么发送给你
later either either to just send you the
在线部分或在课堂上讨论
section online or to discuss it in class
星期一，但我
Monday but I
我真的计划周一开始
I'm really planning Monday to start with
问题四，好好问一个问题
question four and being well to ask a
很多人我都能找到
whole lot of people everybody I can find
关于那个重要的问题是
about that important question is does
深度学习通常会起作用
deep learning usually work how what can
你要确保它有效或给予
you do to make sure it works or give
你自己有更好的机会让它发挥作用
yourself a better chance to have it work
so let's that's that's up for Monday
那就是周一的情况
那么好
then good